{"problemsArray": [
  {"answer": "(-2, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x - 10 for y into the first equation\n(-3x - 10) - x \u003d -2\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-3x - 10 - x \u003d -2\n-2x \u003d 8\nx \u003d -2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x - 10\ny \u003d -3(-2) - 10\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny - x \u003d -2\ny \u003d -3x - 10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 4)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 5\n5(4x + y) \u003d 5(20)\n20x + 5y \u003d 100\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable y\n25x \u003d 100\nSolve for x in the new equation\nx \u003d 100 / 25 \u003d 4\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-5x + 5y \u003d 0\n-5(4) + 5y \u003d 0\n5y + -20 \u003d 0\n5y \u003d 0 + 20 \u003d 20\ny \u003d 20 / 5 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n4x + y \u003d 20\n-5x + 5y \u003d 0", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, -1)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\nx + 4y \u003d 2\n4x + 2y \u003d 143x \u003d 12\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d 12 / 3 \u003d 4\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\nx + 2y \u003d 2\n(4) + 2y \u003d 2\n2y + 4 \u003d 2\n2y \u003d 2 - 4 \u003d -2\ny \u003d -2 / 2 \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx + 2y \u003d 2\n4x + 2y \u003d 14", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -5)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 4\n4(4x + y) \u003d 4(3)\n16x + 4y \u003d 12\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n2y \u003d -10\nSolve for \u0027y\u0027 in the new equation\ny \u003d -10 / 2 \u003d -5\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n16x + 2y \u003d 22\n16x + 2(-5) \u003d 22\n16x + -10 \u003d 22\n16x \u003d 22 + 10 \u003d 32\nx \u003d 32 / 16 \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n4x + y \u003d 3\n16x + 2y \u003d 22", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-2, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in 4x + 9 for y into the first equation\n3(4x + 9) + x \u003d 1\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n12x + 27 + x \u003d 1\n15x \u003d -26\nx \u003d -2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 4x + 9\ny \u003d 4(-2) + 9\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + x \u003d 1\ny \u003d 4x + 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 1)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 2\n2(x + 3y) \u003d 2(7)\n2x + 6y \u003d 14\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n-6y \u003d -6\nSolve for \u0027y\u0027 in the new equation\ny \u003d -6 / -6 \u003d 1\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n2x + 12y \u003d 20\n2x + 12(1) \u003d 20\n2x + 12 \u003d 20\n2x \u003d 20 - 12 \u003d 8\nx \u003d 8 / 2 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx + 3y \u003d 7\n2x + 12y \u003d 20", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, 2)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y + 9 for x into the first equation\n(-2y + 9) + 5y \u003d 15\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-2y + 9 + 5y \u003d 15\n3y \u003d 6\ny \u003d 2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y + 9\nx \u003d -2(2) + 9\nx \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + 5y \u003d 15\nx \u003d -2y + 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x + 21 for y into the first equation\n3(-4x + 21) + x \u003d 8\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-12x + 63 + x \u003d 8\n-9x \u003d -55\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x + 21\ny \u003d -4(5) + 21\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + x \u003d 8\ny \u003d -4x + 21", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in -2x - 1 for y into the first equation\n3(-2x - 1) + x \u003d 12\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-6x - 3 + x \u003d 12\n-3x \u003d 15\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -2x - 1\ny \u003d -2(-3) - 1\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + x \u003d 12\ny \u003d -2x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in y - 3 for x into the first equation\n2(y - 3) + y \u003d -12\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n2y - 6 + y \u003d -12\n3y \u003d -6\ny \u003d -2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d y - 3\nx \u003d (-2) - 3\nx \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2x + y \u003d -12\nx \u003d y - 3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 1)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\nx + y \u003d 8\nx - y \u003d 3-5y \u003d -5\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -5 / -5 \u003d 1\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\nx + 4y \u003d 8\nx + 4(1) \u003d 8\nx + 4 \u003d 8x \u003d 8 - 4 \u003d 4\nx \u003d 4 / 1 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx + 4y \u003d 8\nx - y \u003d 3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in 5y - 6 for x into the first equation\n(5y - 6) + y \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n5y - 6 + y \u003d 0\n6y \u003d 6\ny \u003d 1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 5y - 6\nx \u003d 5(1) - 6\nx \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d 0\nx \u003d 5y - 6", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(0, 3)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\nx + 2y \u003d 12\n2x + 4y \u003d 12x \u003d 0\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d 0 / 1 \u003d 0\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\nx + 4y \u003d 12\n(0) + 4y \u003d 12\n4y + 0 \u003d 12\n4y \u003d 12 - 0 \u003d 12\ny \u003d 12 / 4 \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx + 4y \u003d 12\n2x + 4y \u003d 12", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, -2)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the second equation by 3\n3(x + 8y) \u003d 3(-12)\n3x + 24y \u003d -36\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n22y \u003d -44\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -44 / 22 \u003d -2\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n3x + 2y \u003d 8\n3x + 2(-2) \u003d 8\n3x + -4 \u003d 8\n3x \u003d 8 + 4 \u003d 12\nx \u003d 12 / 3 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n3x + 2y \u003d 8\nx + 8y \u003d -12", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x + 9 for y into the first equation\n(-4x + 9) + 3x \u003d 7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x + 9 + 3x \u003d 7\n-3x \u003d -2\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x + 9\ny \u003d -4(2) + 9\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 3x \u003d 7\ny \u003d -4x + 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 5)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n-2x + y \u003d 13\nx + y \u003d 13x \u003d -12\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d -12 / 3 \u003d -4\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-2x + y \u003d 13\n-2(-4) + y \u003d 13\ny + 8 \u003d 13\ny \u003d 13 - 8 \u003d 5\ny \u003d 5 / 1 \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-2x + y \u003d 13\nx + y \u003d 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x + 24 for y into the first equation\n4(5x + 24) + 3x \u003d 4\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n20x + 96 + 3x \u003d 4\n24x \u003d -92\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x + 24\ny \u003d 5(-4) + 24\ny \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + 3x \u003d 4\ny \u003d 5x + 24", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in -x - 1 for y into the first equation\n(-x - 1) - 2x \u003d -7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-1x - 1 - 2x \u003d -7\n \u003d -6\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x - 1\ny \u003d -(2) - 1\ny \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny - 2x \u003d -7\ny \u003d -x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in -3y - 16 for x into the first equation\n4(-3y - 16) + 2y \u003d -14\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-12y - 64 + 2y \u003d -14\n-10y \u003d 50\ny \u003d -5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -3y - 16\nx \u003d -3(-5) - 16\nx \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + 2y \u003d -14\nx \u003d -3y - 16", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x - 4 for y into the first equation\n(3x - 4) + x \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n3x - 4 + x \u003d 0\n4x \u003d 4\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x - 4\ny \u003d 3(1) - 4\ny \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d 0\ny \u003d 3x - 4", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in 3y + 20 for x into the first equation\n2(3y + 20) - 2y \u003d 20\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n6y + 40 - 2y \u003d 20\n4y \u003d -20\ny \u003d -5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 3y + 20\nx \u003d 3(-5) + 20\nx \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2x - 2y \u003d 20\nx \u003d 3y + 20", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, 0)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n4x + 12y \u003d -12\n12x - 2y \u003d -368x \u003d -24\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d -24 / 8 \u003d -3\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n4x - 2y \u003d -12\n4(-3) - 2y \u003d -12\n-2y + -12 \u003d -12\n-2y \u003d -12 + 12 \u003d 0\ny \u003d 0 / -2 \u003d 0", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n4x - 2y \u003d -12\n12x - 2y \u003d -36", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y + 5 for x into the first equation\n(-2y + 5) + y \u003d 4\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-2y + 5 + y \u003d 4\n-y \u003d -1\ny \u003d 1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y + 5\nx \u003d -2(1) + 5\nx \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d 4\nx \u003d -2y + 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x - 22 for y into the first equation\n(-4x - 22) + 3x \u003d -17\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x - 22 + 3x \u003d -17\n-3x \u003d 5\nx \u003d -5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x - 22\ny \u003d -4(-5) - 22\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 3x \u003d -17\ny \u003d -4x - 22", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -4)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\n3x + 3y \u003d -29\n3x - y \u003d -5-6y \u003d 24\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d 24 / -6 \u003d -4\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n3x + 5y \u003d -29\n3x + 5(-4) \u003d -29\n3x + -20 \u003d -293x \u003d -29 + 20 \u003d -9\nx \u003d -9 / 3 \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n3x + 5y \u003d -29\n3x - y \u003d -5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x + 7 for y into the first equation\n3(3x + 7) + 3x \u003d -27\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n9x + 21 + 3x \u003d -27\n12x \u003d -48\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x + 7\ny \u003d 3(-4) + 7\ny \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3y + 3x \u003d -27\ny \u003d 3x + 7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, -1)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by -2\n-2(-2x + 3y) \u003d -2(7)\n4x - 6y \u003d -14\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n-21y \u003d 21\nSolve for \u0027y\u0027 in the new equation\ny \u003d 21 / -21 \u003d -1\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n4x + 15y \u003d -35\n4x + 15(-1) \u003d -35\n4x + -15 \u003d -35\n4x \u003d -35 + 15 \u003d -20\nx \u003d -20 / 4 \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-2x + 3y \u003d 7\n4x + 15y \u003d -35", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in 4y + 13 for x into the first equation\n(4y + 13) + y \u003d -7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n4y + 13 + y \u003d -7\n5y \u003d -20\ny \u003d -4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 4y + 13\nx \u003d 4(-4) + 13\nx \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d -7\nx \u003d 4y + 13", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, 3)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 2\n2(x - 2y) \u003d 2(-11)\n2x - 4y \u003d -22\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n-5y \u003d -15\nSolve for \u0027y\u0027 in the new equation\ny \u003d -15 / -5 \u003d 3\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n2x + y \u003d -7\n2x + (3) \u003d -7\n2x + 3 \u003d -7\n2x \u003d -7 - 3 \u003d -10\nx \u003d -10 / 2 \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx - 2y \u003d -11\n2x + y \u003d -7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y - 10 for x into the first equation\n4(-2y - 10) + y \u003d -19\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-8y - 40 + y \u003d -19\n-7y \u003d 21\ny \u003d -3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y - 10\nx \u003d -2(-3) - 10\nx \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + y \u003d -19\nx \u003d -2y - 10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, 4)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n-x - 2y \u003d 9\n-2x + 3y \u003d 6-x \u003d -3\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d -3 / -1 \u003d 3\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-x + 3y \u003d 9\n-(3) + 3y \u003d 9\n3y + -3 \u003d 9\n3y \u003d 9 + 3 \u003d 12\ny \u003d 12 / 3 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-x + 3y \u003d 9\n-2x + 3y \u003d 6", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, 4)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\nx - 2y \u003d 7\n-2x + 3y \u003d 22-3x \u003d 15\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d 15 / -3 \u003d -5\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\nx + 3y \u003d 7\n(-5) + 3y \u003d 7\n3y + -5 \u003d 7\n3y \u003d 7 + 5 \u003d 12\ny \u003d 12 / 3 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx + 3y \u003d 7\n-2x + 3y \u003d 22", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-2, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in -2x - 9 for y into the first equation\n2(-2x - 9) + x \u003d -12\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x - 18 + x \u003d -12\n-2x \u003d 6\nx \u003d -2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -2x - 9\ny \u003d -2(-2) - 9\ny \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + x \u003d -12\ny \u003d -2x - 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x - 19 for y into the first equation\n2(5x - 19) + 4x \u003d 18\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n10x - 38 + 4x \u003d 18\n12x \u003d 56\nx \u003d 4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x - 19\ny \u003d 5(4) - 19\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + 4x \u003d 18\ny \u003d 5x - 19", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x - 22 for y into the first equation\n2(5x - 22) - x \u003d -8\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n10x - 44 - x \u003d -8\n12x \u003d 36\nx \u003d 4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x - 22\ny \u003d 5(4) - 22\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y - x \u003d -8\ny \u003d 5x - 22", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, -3)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\n4x + 4y \u003d 7\n4x + 9y \u003d -116y \u003d -18\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -18 / 6 \u003d -3\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n4x + 3y \u003d 7\n4x + 3(-3) \u003d 7\n4x + -9 \u003d 74x \u003d 7 + 9 \u003d 16\nx \u003d 16 / 4 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n4x + 3y \u003d 7\n4x + 9y \u003d -11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -3)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 4\n4(3x + 4y) \u003d 4(-24)\n12x + 16y \u003d -96\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable y\n8x \u003d -32\nSolve for x in the new equation\nx \u003d -32 / 8 \u003d -4\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n4x + 16y \u003d -64\n4(-4) + 16y \u003d -64\n16y + -16 \u003d -64\n16y \u003d -64 + 16 \u003d -48\ny \u003d -48 / 16 \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n3x + 4y \u003d -24\n4x + 16y \u003d -64", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 3)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the second equation by -1\n-1(2x + 5y) \u003d -1(23)\n-2x - 5y \u003d -23\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n-6y \u003d -18\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -18 / -6 \u003d 3\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n-2x + y \u003d -5\n-2x + (3) \u003d -5\n-2x + 3 \u003d -5\n-2x \u003d -5 - 3 \u003d -8\nx \u003d -8 / -2 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-2x + y \u003d -5\n2x + 5y \u003d 23", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 4)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n3x + 6y \u003d -7\n6x - y \u003d -103x \u003d -3\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d -3 / 3 \u003d -1\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n3x - y \u003d -7\n3(-1) - y \u003d -7\n-y + -3 \u003d -7\n-y \u003d -7 + 3 \u003d -4\ny \u003d -4 / -1 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n3x - y \u003d -7\n6x - y \u003d -10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 3)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\nx - 2y \u003d 5\n-2x + 2y \u003d 8-3x \u003d 3\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d 3 / -3 \u003d -1\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\nx + 2y \u003d 5\n(-1) + 2y \u003d 5\n2y + -1 \u003d 5\n2y \u003d 5 + 1 \u003d 6\ny \u003d 6 / 2 \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx + 2y \u003d 5\n-2x + 2y \u003d 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in 3y + 13 for x into the first equation\n4(3y + 13) + 3y \u003d 7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n12y + 52 + 3y \u003d 7\n15y \u003d -45\ny \u003d -3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 3y + 13\nx \u003d 3(-3) + 13\nx \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + 3y \u003d 7\nx \u003d 3y + 13", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, 5)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n-x + 2y \u003d 10\n2x + y \u003d -53x \u003d -15\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d -15 / 3 \u003d -5\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-x + y \u003d 10\n-(-5) + y \u003d 10\ny + 5 \u003d 10\ny \u003d 10 - 5 \u003d 5\ny \u003d 5 / 1 \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-x + y \u003d 10\n2x + y \u003d -5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in -2x + 6 for y into the first equation\n2(-2x + 6) + x \u003d 9\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x + 12 + x \u003d 9\n-2x \u003d -3\nx \u003d 1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -2x + 6\ny \u003d -2(1) + 6\ny \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + x \u003d 9\ny \u003d -2x + 6", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y - 9 for x into the first equation\n4(-2y - 9) + y \u003d -8\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-8y - 36 + y \u003d -8\n-7y \u003d 28\ny \u003d -4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y - 9\nx \u003d -2(-4) - 9\nx \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + y \u003d -8\nx \u003d -2y - 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y + 6 for x into the first equation\n(-2y + 6) + y \u003d 5\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-2y + 6 + y \u003d 5\n-y \u003d -1\ny \u003d 1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y + 6\nx \u003d -2(1) + 6\nx \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d 5\nx \u003d -2y + 6", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -x - 2 for y into the first equation\n4(-x - 2) + 3x \u003d -3\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x - 8 + 3x \u003d -3\n \u003d 5\nx \u003d -5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x - 2\ny \u003d -(-5) - 2\ny \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + 3x \u003d -3\ny \u003d -x - 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -4y + 11 for x into the first equation\n3(-4y + 11) + 5y \u003d 12\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-12y + 33 + 5y \u003d 12\n-7y \u003d -21\ny \u003d 3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -4y + 11\nx \u003d -4(3) + 11\nx \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + 5y \u003d 12\nx \u003d -4y + 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in y + 3 for x into the first equation\n(y + 3) - 2y \u003d 7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n1y + 3 - 2y \u003d 7\n-y \u003d 4\ny \u003d -4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d y + 3\nx \u003d (-4) + 3\nx \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx - 2y \u003d 7\nx \u003d y + 3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 4)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\nx + y \u003d 18\nx - 4y \u003d -14-8y \u003d -32\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -32 / -8 \u003d 4\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\nx + 4y \u003d 18\nx + 4(4) \u003d 18\nx + 16 \u003d 18x \u003d 18 - 16 \u003d 2\nx \u003d 2 / 1 \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx + 4y \u003d 18\nx - 4y \u003d -14", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x + 10 for y into the first equation\n(3x + 10) + 2x \u003d -10\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n3x + 10 + 2x \u003d -10\n4x \u003d -20\nx \u003d -4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x + 10\ny \u003d 3(-4) + 10\ny \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 2x \u003d -10\ny \u003d 3x + 10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -3)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\nx + y \u003d 5\nx - 2y \u003d 8-y \u003d 3\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d 3 / -1 \u003d -3\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\nx - y \u003d 5\nx - (-3) \u003d 5\nx + 3 \u003d 5x \u003d 5 - 3 \u003d 2\nx \u003d 2 / 1 \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx - y \u003d 5\nx - 2y \u003d 8", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in -y - 1 for x into the first equation\n(-y - 1) - y \u003d 5\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-1y - 1 - y \u003d 5\n-2y \u003d 6\ny \u003d -3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y - 1\nx \u003d -(-3) - 1\nx \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx - y \u003d 5\nx \u003d -y - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, 1)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n-x - 5y \u003d 0\n-5x + 3y \u003d -12-4x \u003d -12\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d -12 / -4 \u003d 3\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-x + 3y \u003d 0\n-(3) + 3y \u003d 0\n3y + -3 \u003d 0\n3y \u003d 0 + 3 \u003d 3\ny \u003d 3 / 3 \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-x + 3y \u003d 0\n-5x + 3y \u003d -12", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -3)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n3x - 2y \u003d 9\n-2x + 2y \u003d -16-5x \u003d -25\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d -25 / -5 \u003d 5\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n3x + 2y \u003d 9\n3(5) + 2y \u003d 9\n2y + 15 \u003d 9\n2y \u003d 9 - 15 \u003d -6\ny \u003d -6 / 2 \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n3x + 2y \u003d 9\n-2x + 2y \u003d -16", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(0, -1)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n3x - 3y \u003d -2\n-3x + 2y \u003d -2-6x \u003d 0\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d 0 / -6 \u003d 0\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n3x + 2y \u003d -2\n3(0) + 2y \u003d -2\n2y + 0 \u003d -2\n2y \u003d -2 - 0 \u003d -2\ny \u003d -2 / 2 \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n3x + 2y \u003d -2\n-3x + 2y \u003d -2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, -5)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\nx + y \u003d 0\nx + y \u003d -102y \u003d -10\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -10 / 2 \u003d -5\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\nx - y \u003d 0\nx - (-5) \u003d 0\nx + 5 \u003d 0x \u003d 0 - 5 \u003d -5\nx \u003d -5 / 1 \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx - y \u003d 0\nx + y \u003d -10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -1)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n-x + y \u003d -6\nx + 4y \u003d -22x \u003d 4\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d 4 / 2 \u003d 2\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-x + 4y \u003d -6\n-(2) + 4y \u003d -6\n4y + -2 \u003d -6\n4y \u003d -6 + 2 \u003d -4\ny \u003d -4 / 4 \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-x + 4y \u003d -6\nx + 4y \u003d -2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-2, 3)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\nx + y \u003d 7\nx + 4y \u003d 101y \u003d 3\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d 3 / 1 \u003d 3\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\nx + 3y \u003d 7\nx + 3(3) \u003d 7\nx + 9 \u003d 7x \u003d 7 - 9 \u003d -2\nx \u003d -2 / 1 \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\nx + 3y \u003d 7\nx + 4y \u003d 10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in 5x + 10 for y into the first equation\n(5x + 10) + 5x \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n5x + 10 + 5x \u003d 0\n6x \u003d -10\nx \u003d -1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 5x + 10\ny \u003d 5(-1) + 10\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 5x \u003d 0\ny \u003d 5x + 10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y - 11 for x into the first equation\n(-2y - 11) + y \u003d -7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-2y - 11 + y \u003d -7\n-y \u003d 4\ny \u003d -4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y - 11\nx \u003d -2(-4) - 11\nx \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + y \u003d -7\nx \u003d -2y - 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y + 11 for x into the first equation\n2(-2y + 11) + y \u003d 7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-4y + 22 + y \u003d 7\n-3y \u003d -15\ny \u003d 5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y + 11\nx \u003d -2(5) + 11\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2x + y \u003d 7\nx \u003d -2y + 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-2, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in -x - 1 for y into the first equation\n(-x - 1) + 4x \u003d -7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-1x - 1 + 4x \u003d -7\n \u003d -6\nx \u003d -2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -x - 1\ny \u003d -(-2) - 1\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 4x \u003d -7\ny \u003d -x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in 4x - 13 for y into the first equation\n(4x - 13) + 4x \u003d 11\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n4x - 13 + 4x \u003d 11\n5x \u003d 24\nx \u003d 3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 4x - 13\ny \u003d 4(3) - 13\ny \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 4x \u003d 11\ny \u003d 4x - 13", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in 4x - 3 for y into the first equation\n(4x - 3) - x \u003d 3\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n4x - 3 - x \u003d 3\n5x \u003d 6\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 4x - 3\ny \u003d 4(2) - 3\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny - x \u003d 3\ny \u003d 4x - 3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in -3y + 11 for x into the first equation\n3(-3y + 11) + y \u003d 9\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-9y + 33 + y \u003d 9\n-8y \u003d -24\ny \u003d 3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -3y + 11\nx \u003d -3(3) + 11\nx \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + y \u003d 9\nx \u003d -3y + 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -3)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\n4x + 4y \u003d -8\n4x + 12y \u003d -328y \u003d -24\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -24 / 8 \u003d -3\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n4x + 4y \u003d -8\n4x + 4(-3) \u003d -8\n4x + -12 \u003d -84x \u003d -8 + 12 \u003d 4\nx \u003d 4 / 4 \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n4x + 4y \u003d -8\n4x + 12y \u003d -32", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 1)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x - 5 for y into the first equation\n(3x - 5) + x \u003d 3\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n3x - 5 + x \u003d 3\n4x \u003d 8\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x - 5\ny \u003d 3(2) - 5\ny \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d 3\ny \u003d 3x - 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in 3x - 9 for y into the first equation\n4(3x - 9) + 2x \u003d 20\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n12x - 36 + 2x \u003d 20\n16x \u003d 56\nx \u003d 4\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 3x - 9\ny \u003d 3(4) - 9\ny \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + 2x \u003d 20\ny \u003d 3x - 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -2)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n2x + 6y \u003d 8\n6x - 2y \u003d 164x \u003d 8\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d 8 / 4 \u003d 2\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n2x - 2y \u003d 8\n2(2) - 2y \u003d 8\n-2y + 4 \u003d 8\n-2y \u003d 8 - 4 \u003d 4\ny \u003d 4 / -2 \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n2x - 2y \u003d 8\n6x - 2y \u003d 16", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -2x - 10 for y into the first equation\n4(-2x - 10) - 2x \u003d -10\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-8x - 40 - 2x \u003d -10\n-4x \u003d 30\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -2x - 10\ny \u003d -2(-3) - 10\ny \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y - 2x \u003d -10\ny \u003d -2x - 10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(4, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in 5y - 11 for x into the first equation\n3(5y - 11) + 2y \u003d 18\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n15y - 33 + 2y \u003d 18\n17y \u003d 51\ny \u003d 3\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 5y - 11\nx \u003d 5(3) - 11\nx \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + 2y \u003d 18\nx \u003d 5y - 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in -y + 6 for x into the first equation\n(-y + 6) + 3y \u003d 16\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-1y + 6 + 3y \u003d 16\n2y \u003d 10\ny \u003d 5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y + 6\nx \u003d -(5) + 6\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + 3y \u003d 16\nx \u003d -y + 6", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 3)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 2\n2(-x + y) \u003d 2(4)\n-2x + 2y \u003d 8\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n-y \u003d -3\nSolve for \u0027y\u0027 in the new equation\ny \u003d -3 / -1 \u003d 3\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n-2x + 3y \u003d 11\n-2x + 3(3) \u003d 11\n-2x + 9 \u003d 11\n-2x \u003d 11 - 9 \u003d 2\nx \u003d 2 / -2 \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-x + y \u003d 4\n-2x + 3y \u003d 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -4)", "explanation": "Plug in -y - 2 for x into the first equation\n4(-y - 2) - 2y \u003d 16\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-4y - 8 - 2y \u003d 16\n-6y \u003d 24\ny \u003d -4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y - 2\nx \u003d -(-4) - 2\nx \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x - 2y \u003d 16\nx \u003d -y - 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(3, -5)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\n2x + 2y \u003d 16\n2x + y \u003d 13y \u003d -15\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -15 / 3 \u003d -5\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n2x - 2y \u003d 16\n2x - 2(-5) \u003d 16\n2x + 10 \u003d 162x \u003d 16 - 10 \u003d 6\nx \u003d 6 / 2 \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n2x - 2y \u003d 16\n2x + y \u003d 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-2, 4)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 4\n4(-x + 3y) \u003d 4(14)\n-4x + 12y \u003d 56\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n-3y \u003d -12\nSolve for \u0027y\u0027 in the new equation\ny \u003d -12 / -3 \u003d 4\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n-4x + 15y \u003d 68\n-4x + 15(4) \u003d 68\n-4x + 60 \u003d 68\n-4x \u003d 68 - 60 \u003d 8\nx \u003d 8 / -4 \u003d -2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-x + 3y \u003d 14\n-4x + 15y \u003d 68", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 0)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 3\n3(-x + 4y) \u003d 3(-2)\n-3x + 12y \u003d -6\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n4y \u003d 0\nSolve for \u0027y\u0027 in the new equation\ny \u003d 0 / 4 \u003d 0\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n-3x + 8y \u003d -6\n-3x + 8(0) \u003d -6\n-3x + 0 \u003d -6\n-3x \u003d -6 - 0 \u003d -6\nx \u003d -6 / -3 \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-x + 4y \u003d -2\n-3x + 8y \u003d -6", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(0, 5)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n4x + 12y \u003d 20\n12x + 4y \u003d 208x \u003d 0\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d 0 / 8 \u003d 0\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n4x + 4y \u003d 20\n4(0) + 4y \u003d 20\n4y + 0 \u003d 20\n4y \u003d 20 - 0 \u003d 20\ny \u003d 20 / 4 \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n4x + 4y \u003d 20\n12x + 4y \u003d 20", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in -2y - 9 for x into the first equation\n(-2y - 9) - y \u003d 6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-2y - 9 - y \u003d 6\n-3y \u003d 15\ny \u003d -5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -2y - 9\nx \u003d -2(-5) - 9\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx - y \u003d 6\nx \u003d -2y - 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 1)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 3\n3(4x + y) \u003d 3(9)\n12x + 3y \u003d 27\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable y\n15x \u003d 30\nSolve for x in the new equation\nx \u003d 30 / 15 \u003d 2\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-3x + 3y \u003d -3\n-3(2) + 3y \u003d -3\n3y + -6 \u003d -3\n3y \u003d -3 + 6 \u003d 3\ny \u003d 3 / 3 \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n4x + y \u003d 9\n-3x + 3y \u003d -3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -1)", "explanation": "Plug in 5y + 6 for x into the first equation\n3(5y + 6) + 3y \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n15y + 18 + 3y \u003d 0\n18y \u003d -18\ny \u003d -1\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d 5y + 6\nx \u003d 5(-1) + 6\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x + 3y \u003d 0\nx \u003d 5y + 6", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 0)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 5\n5(5x + 2y) \u003d 5(5)\n25x + 10y \u003d 25\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable y\n23x \u003d 23\nSolve for x in the new equation\nx \u003d 23 / 23 \u003d 1\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n2x + 10y \u003d 2\n2(1) + 10y \u003d 2\n10y + 2 \u003d 2\n10y \u003d 2 - 2 \u003d 0\ny \u003d 0 / 10 \u003d 0", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n5x + 2y \u003d 5\n2x + 10y \u003d 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, -5)", "explanation": "Plug in x - 10 for y into the first equation\n4(x - 10) + 4x \u003d 0\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n4x - 40 + 4x \u003d 0\n8x \u003d 40\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d x - 10\ny \u003d (5) - 10\ny \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + 4x \u003d 0\ny \u003d x - 10", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -2)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, x\n3x + 3y \u003d -5\n3x - y \u003d -71y \u003d -2\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -2 / 1 \u003d -2\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n3x - 2y \u003d -5\n3x - 2(-2) \u003d -5\n3x + 4 \u003d -53x \u003d -5 - 4 \u003d -9\nx \u003d -9 / 3 \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n3x - 2y \u003d -5\n3x - y \u003d -7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in -y + 0 for x into the first equation\n(-y + 0) + 5y \u003d 20\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-1y + 0 + 5y \u003d 20\n4y \u003d 20\ny \u003d 5\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y + 0\nx \u003d -(5) + 0\nx \u003d -5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\nx + 5y \u003d 20\nx \u003d -y + 0", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-5, 4)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 5\n5(-2x + 4y) \u003d 5(26)\n-10x + 20y \u003d 130\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable y\n-7x \u003d 35\nSolve for x in the new equation\nx \u003d 35 / -7 \u003d -5\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-3x + 20y \u003d 95\n-3(-5) + 20y \u003d 95\n20y + 15 \u003d 95\n20y \u003d 95 - 15 \u003d 80\ny \u003d 80 / 20 \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-2x + 4y \u003d 26\n-3x + 20y \u003d 95", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in y - 5 for x into the first equation\n4(y - 5) + 5y \u003d 16\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n4y - 20 + 5y \u003d 16\n9y \u003d 36\ny \u003d 4\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d y - 5\nx \u003d (4) - 5\nx \u003d -1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4x + 5y \u003d 16\nx \u003d y - 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in x + 3 for y into the first equation\n4(x + 3) + x \u003d 22\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n4x + 12 + x \u003d 22\n8x \u003d 10\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d x + 3\ny \u003d (2) + 3\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n4y + x \u003d 22\ny \u003d x + 3", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-4, 0)", "explanation": "Subtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable, y:\n-x - 3y \u003d 4\n-3x + 4y \u003d 12-2x \u003d 8\nSolve for x in thenew equation\nx \u003d 8 / -2 \u003d -4\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-x + 4y \u003d 4\n-(-4) + 4y \u003d 4\n4y + 4 \u003d 4\n4y \u003d 4 - 4 \u003d 0\ny \u003d 0 / 4 \u003d 0", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-x + 4y \u003d 4\n-3x + 4y \u003d 12", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, 4)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the second equation by -2\n-2(x + 2y) \u003d -2(9)\n-2x - 4y \u003d -18\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n-5y \u003d -20\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d -20 / -5 \u003d 4\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n-2x + y \u003d 2\n-2x + (4) \u003d 2\n-2x + 4 \u003d 2\n-2x \u003d 2 - 4 \u003d -2\nx \u003d -2 / -2 \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-2x + y \u003d 2\nx + 2y \u003d 9", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-1, -3)", "explanation": "Plug in 2x - 1 for y into the first equation\n(2x - 1) + 4x \u003d -7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n2x - 1 + 4x \u003d -7\n3x \u003d -6\nx \u003d -1\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 2x - 1\ny \u003d 2(-1) - 1\ny \u003d -3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 4x \u003d -7\ny \u003d 2x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, 0)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the second equation by -1\n-1(x + 12y) \u003d -1(5)\n-x - 12y \u003d -5\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n-16y \u003d 0\nSolve for y in the new equation\ny \u003d 0 / -16 \u003d 0\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n-x + 4y \u003d -5\n-x + 4(0) \u003d -5\n-x + 0 \u003d -5\n-x \u003d -5 - 0 \u003d -5\nx \u003d -5 / -1 \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n-x + 4y \u003d -5\nx + 12y \u003d 5", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, -4)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 4\n4(2x + y) \u003d 4(-10)\n8x + 4y \u003d -40\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable y\n13x \u003d -39\nSolve for x in the new equation\nx \u003d -39 / 13 \u003d -3\nFind the value of y by plugging in the value for x into one of the original equations\n-5x + 4y \u003d -1\n-5(-3) + 4y \u003d -1\n4y + 15 \u003d -1\n4y \u003d -1 - 15 \u003d -16\ny \u003d -16 / 4 \u003d -4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n2x + y \u003d -10\n-5x + 4y \u003d -1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, 2)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x - 7 for y into the first equation\n2(-3x - 7) - x \u003d 7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-6x - 14 - x \u003d 7\n-4x \u003d 21\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x - 7\ny \u003d -3(-3) - 7\ny \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y - x \u003d 7\ny \u003d -3x - 7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, -3)", "explanation": "Get one of the variables to have the same coefficient in both equations\nMultiply the first equation by 2\n2(2x + y) \u003d 2(1)\n4x + 2y \u003d 2\nSubtract the two equations from each other to eliminate the variable x\n-3y \u003d 9\nSolve for \u0027y\u0027 in the new equation\ny \u003d 9 / -3 \u003d -3\nFind the value of x by plugging in the value for y into one of the original equations\n4x + 5y \u003d -7\n4x + 5(-3) \u003d -7\n4x + -15 \u003d -7\n4x \u003d -7 + 15 \u003d 8\nx \u003d 8 / 4 \u003d 2", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by elimination:\n2x + y \u003d 1\n4x + 5y \u003d -7", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 3)", "explanation": "Plug in 2x - 1 for y into the first equation\n(2x - 1) + x \u003d 5\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n2x - 1 + x \u003d 5\n3x \u003d 6\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d 2x - 1\ny \u003d 2(2) - 1\ny \u003d 3", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + x \u003d 5\ny \u003d 2x - 1", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(-3, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in -2x - 2 for y into the first equation\n2(-2x - 2) + x \u003d 5\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x - 4 + x \u003d 5\n-2x \u003d 9\nx \u003d -3\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -2x - 2\ny \u003d -2(-3) - 2\ny \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y + x \u003d 5\ny \u003d -2x - 2", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(2, 5)", "explanation": "Plug in -3x + 11 for y into the first equation\n2(-3x + 11) - 2x \u003d 6\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-6x + 22 - 2x \u003d 6\n-4x \u003d -16\nx \u003d 2\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -3x + 11\ny \u003d -3(2) + 11\ny \u003d 5", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n2y - 2x \u003d 6\ny \u003d -3x + 11", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(5, 4)", "explanation": "Plug in -4x + 24 for y into the first equation\n(-4x + 24) + 2x \u003d 14\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for x\n-4x + 24 + 2x \u003d 14\n-3x \u003d -10\nx \u003d 5\nPlug in this x value into the second equation to find the value of y\ny \u003d -4x + 24\ny \u003d -4(5) + 24\ny \u003d 4", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\ny + 2x \u003d 14\ny \u003d -4x + 24", "type": "text"},
  {"answer": "(1, -2)", "explanation": "Plug in -y - 1 for x into the first equation\n3(-y - 1) - 2y \u003d 7\nSimplify the equation to get an answer for y\n-3y - 3 - 2y \u003d 7\n-5y \u003d 10\ny \u003d -2\nPlug in this y value into the second equation to find the value of x\nx \u003d -y - 1\nx \u003d -(-2) - 1\nx \u003d 1", "prompt": "(x, y) \u003d", "question": "Solve for x and y by substitution:\n3x - 2y \u003d 7\nx \u003d -y - 1", "type": "text"}
]}